<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<kiln:root xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:kiln="http://www.kcl.ac.uk/artshums/depts/ddh/kiln/ns/1.0"
  xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform">

  <kiln:parent>
    <xi:include href="base.xml"/>
  </kiln:parent>

  <kiln:child>
    <kiln:block name="title">
      <kiln:super/>
      <xsl:text>Terms of Use and Online Privacy</xsl:text>
    </kiln:block>

    <kiln:block name="content">
      <div class="content no-hero contact white-bg">
        <div class="row">
          <div class="column medium-9">
            <h1>Terms of Use and Online Privacy</h1>
          </div>
        </div>
        
        
        <div class="row selected-record-summary relative">
          <div class="columns medium-9 record">
            
            <h3>Terms of Use</h3>
            
            <p>The content of the REED collections on this website, including the glossaries and bibliography, is licensed under a <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</a>. This means that you may copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format, as well as remix, transform, and build upon the material, but only under the following terms: you may not use the material for commercial purposes, and you must distribute it under the same license as the original. You must also credit REED Online as the original source, provide a link to the license, and state whether any changes were made to the content.</p>
            <p>To cite REED Online please include the website name REED Online and the URL of the website home page or, when relevant, the individual record, as well as the date of access. If you are citing an individual record, please also include the editor's name and name of the collection. For citing an individual record, using MLA 8, we recommend the following format:</p>
            <p>  Somerset, J. Alan B. (ed). "Staffordshire." <em>REED Online</em>, <a href="https://ereed.org/records/staff-ridm55010640/">https://ereed.org/records/staff-ridm55010640/</a>. Accessed 29 Mar. 2018.</p>
            
            <p>The REED Online website and all content provided on it is protected by copyright and other applicable intellectual property and proprietary rights laws.</p>
            <p>The name REED Online and the associated logos <img src="{$kiln:assets-path}/images/terms-reed-logo-small.png" alt="REED logo" /> and <img src="{$kiln:assets-path}/images/terms-reedonline-logo-small.png" alt="REED Online logo" /> may not be used without permission of the REED project.</p>
        <br/>
            <h3>Online Privacy and Data Collection</h3>
        
              <p>We use data gathered by <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> to ensure that the site is meeting your
                needs, and to see where there is room for improvement. All user data that we receive
                is completely anonymous. However, your domain name or IP address may identify you
                depending on the naming standards followed by your Internet service provider. You
                may wish to ask them about their policies and practices.</p>

              <p>We use Google Analytics to track how you use this website, including information
                about:</p>
              <ul>
                <li><p>How long you stay on the site</p></li>
                <li><p>What search terms you use on the site</p></li>
                <li><p>Which, and how many, pages you visit while you’re on the site</p></li>
                <li><p>What page you’re on when you decide to leave the site</p></li>
              </ul>

              <p>If you don’t want Google Analytics to record how you use our website, you can opt
                out by using this <a href="https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout">browser
                  extension</a> or setting your browser to private mode.</p>
              <hr/>
            
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </kiln:block>
  </kiln:child>

</kiln:root>
