<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:base="tei/" xml:id="digital_methodology">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Digital Methodology</title>
                <author>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>version 1, released <date when-iso="2017-03-03">3 March
                    2017</date></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority><orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>University of Toronto</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>170 St George Street, Suite 810</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Toronto, Ontario, Canada</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>M5R 2M8</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </authority>
                <availability>
                    <p>Copyright <orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>,
                            <date>2017</date></p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Distributed
                        under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0
                        International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) licence.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>Records of Early English Drama</title>
            </seriesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital. Information on original sources for transcriptions can be accessed
                    via the Document Descriptions.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Records of Early English Drama (REED) is an international scholarly project that
                    is establishing for the first time the context from which the drama of
                    Shakespeare and his contemporaries grew. Founded in 1976, REED has worked since
                    then to locate, transcribe, and edit historical documents containing evidence of
                    drama, secular music, and other communal entertainment and ceremony from the
                    Middle Ages until 1642, when the Puritans closed the London theatres.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change/>
            <!-- Add new major milestone changes to top, within <change> tags. For instance, addition of new collections. -->
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="introduction">
                <head>Introduction</head>
                <p>REED Online records and editorial materials have been marked up using the TEI
                    encoding scheme. The raw files can be downloaded from REED's <ref
                        target="https://github.com/REEDProject/Collections">Collections</ref>
                    repository on GitHub.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="tags">
                <head>EATS Tags</head>
                <p>The web application EATS (the entity authority tool set) has been used to 'tag'
                    records with terms of interest to REED users. Each tag can be used to filter
                    search results. Each tag also has its own page, accessed by clicking on a
                    highlighted tag in the records or editorial materials.</p>
                <p>As with REED print indexes, only terms and concepts deemed significant to users
                    have been tagged. This is why not all occupations, for instance, have been
                    tagged.</p>
                <p>At this time, the tagging is not comprehensive. It is, instead, being used as a
                    pointer to get users to the relevant document. A record may include the word
                    'piper' more than once but usually the first instance alone has been tagged;
                    thus, a reader should never assume a tagged word is the only instance of that
                    word or concept in the record. The first-instance rule, however, is not
                    absolute. Additional tags may be used to clarify pronouns or other unclear
                    references.</p>
                <p>Along with record transcriptions, record headings are always tagged as are
                    endnotes (first instance). The document descriptions and Introduction are
                    lightly tagged, with more comprehensive tagging of the Introduction planned for
                    the future. For now, the web browser's search should help find terms of interest
                    in the Introduction. Translations are not tagged.</p>
                <p>Because some tags appear in endnotes, document descriptions, marginalia, or
                    footnotes, they will not be visible without first opening the accordions
                    underneath the record transcription. This is a good place to check if a tag is
                    not immediately apparent within the record transcription itself.</p>
                <p>As the database grows, terms within the filters will multiply, so the current set
                    does not represent a model for the entire REED corpus, only the uploaded
                    collections.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="terminology">
                <head>Tag Terminology</head>
                <p>Due to the difficulty of classifying musical terms like 'piping,' 'pipe music,'
                    etc, as either entertainers or entertainments, we have classed all such terms as
                    entertainers. Therefore, the tag 'pipers' encompasses all kinds of piping
                    activity, allowing the researcher to search more efficiently. Similarly, records
                    that mention 'music' have been tagged with 'musicians,' and records that mention
                    'dancing' have been tagged with 'dancers.'</p>
                <p>To tag entertainer terms that can mean more than one thing, especially those in
                    Latin, we have relied on the wording of the record rather than editorial
                    judgments. Thus, 'histrio, histrionis' and 'mimus, mimi' are tagged as
                    'entertainers, unspecified.' For more on Latin performance terms and their
                    meanings, see REED's <ref
                        target="http://reed.utoronto.ca/principal-terms-relating-to-performance/"
                        >Anglo-Latin Wordbook</ref>.</p>
                <p>Under the Collectives, Occupation filter, the 'parish clergy' tag includes
                    vicars, rectors, ministers, curates, and parsons; 'cathedral clergy' includes
                    deans and canons; and 'monastic orders' includes abbots, priors, monks, friars,
                    abbesses, and nuns.</p>
                <p>The Record Types filter allows users to refine results by the type of source
                    document. As more collections are added to the database, more varieties will
                    appear within each category. The Central Government and Royal category will
                    eventually include records from the courts of law such as the Assizes, Chancery,
                    Common Pleas, Exchequer, King's/Queen's Bench, and Star Chamber. The Local
                    Government category will include borough records (such as city accounts, court
                    records, minutes, and orders) and county records (such as quarter and petty
                    sessions). The Church category will include diocesan administration (such as
                    ecclesiastical visitations), records of the ecclesiastical courts, and parish
                    accounts. The Family category will include accounts, correspondence, diaries and
                    commonplace books, wills, and inventories.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="filters">
                <head>How Filters Work</head>
                <p>By default, all records in the database are displayed on the Search the Records
                    page. Filters along the left side of the page can be used to refine the results.
                    See <ref target="/howto/search/">Search Tips</ref> for basic instructions on
                    filters and searching.</p>
                <p>After a term is selected within the filters, the table of results will reload,
                    showing only records tagged with that term. The filters will also reload.
                    Selecting 'Corpus Christi Day' from the Calendar Days, Liturgical filter will
                    find records tagged with the term 'Corpus Christi Day.' Under the Calendar Days,
                    Liturgical filter, other days may still be listed because they appear in records
                    tagged with 'Corpus Christi Day.' Similarly, selecting 'female' under the
                    People, Gender filter will find records containing female named individuals, but
                    the list of named individuals under the People, Named filter will include male
                    and unknown names, as well as female names, because they appear in records with
                    a female individual.</p>
                <p>In most instances, selecting a term from the filters will find records tagged
                    with that term. In the case of four filters, however, the search results will
                    also include records with associated tags: (1) Location (2) Collectives,
                    Occupation, (3) Entertainers, Type, and (4) Drama, Type.</p>
                <p>1) Searching for a location will find not only records tagged with that location,
                    but also any records tagged with places within that location. A search for the
                    county of 'Staffordshire' will also find any settlements or features contained
                    within Staffordshire, even if Staffordshire itself is not tagged in those
                    records.</p>
                <p>2) Searching for 'mayors' under Collectives, Occupation will find not only
                    records with the word 'mayor/s,' but also records with named mayors. A search on
                    any occupation works like this.</p>
                <p>3) Searching for 'players' under Entertainers, Type will find records with
                    generic players, named players, or patronized troupes of players, such as the
                    15th earl of Derby's players. To refine the results and find only patronized
                    troupes who are players, select 'patronized' under Entertainers, Status. A
                    search on any entertainer type works like this.</p>
                <p>4) Searching for 'plays' under Drama, Type will find records with generic plays
                    or titled plays such as 'Hamlet.' To refine the results and find only titled
                    plays, select 'titled' under Drama, Status. A search on any drama type works
                    like this.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="characters">
                <head>Unusual Characters and Screen Display</head>
                <p>Some records include characters that are not currently part of Unicode, for
                    example, the punctus elevatus. In order for these to display properly, users
                    must install one of three fonts that are provided for free via MUFI at
                    http://folk.uib.no/hnooh/mufi/fonts/. The fonts we recommend are Cardo,
                    Junicode, or Palemonas MUFI.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="maps">
                <head>Maps</head>
                <p>Each record in the REED database has been tagged with locational information to
                    the extent that this is possible. Locations are hierarchically arranged by
                    Country, County, and Settlement. Records are tagged with all locations mentioned
                    or hierarchically implied as explained above under 'How Filters Work.' They
                    might also be tagged with significant local Features when explicitly named, such
                    as identified and locatable buildings (for instance, churches or manor houses).
                    When no such explicit location is mentioned, the record will be mapped to a
                    generic location within the settlement.</p>
                <p>The maps for REED Online are designed to show a specific location and all its
                    related records, that is, records that have been tagged with that location.
                    Therefore, a search by location for the Settlement 'Stafford' will bring up all
                    the records tagged with that location. However, the search results do not
                    include a map of that location. To see it on a map, one must select an
                    individual record, and then click on the location 'Stafford' in the header for
                    that record. Clicking on Stafford brings up the Stafford page; click on the
                    'Map' tab to see the map showing the location of Stafford and all related
                    records. (Clicking on 'Staffordshire' in the header would bring up the county
                    page and its map tab.)</p>
                <p>The 'Map' tab presents an interactive map which shows the selected location
                    highlighted in yellow, and all related records as circular symbols or clusters
                    of symbols in red. In the bottom right corner of the map, there is a 'Legend'
                    icon – click on this for a detailed legend of map symbols. In the top right
                    corner, there is a 'Layers' icon – click on this for controls to switch the base
                    map from the map showing EREED coverage by county (the default) to a shaded
                    relief map, or to a modern street map (<ref
                        target="http://www.openstreetmap.org/">Openstreetmap.org</ref> as delivered
                    by <ref target="https://www.mapbox.com/">Mapbox.com</ref>). Here you will also
                    find checkboxes to control several EREED reference layers, for place symbols,
                    place labels, and pre-1642 roads. In the top left corner of the map, there is a
                    'Zoom' control, and in the bottom left corner a 'Scale bar.'</p>
                <p>For more information about the information and data sources used for the map,
                    please refer to the REED Patrons and Performances website pages <ref
                        target="https://library2.utm.utoronto.ca/otra/reed/content/about-maps">'About the
                        maps'</ref> and <ref
                            target="https://library2.utm.utoronto.ca/otra/reed/sources-of-evidence">'Sources of
                        evidence'</ref>. Much of the same data and methods have been used for the
                    REED Online maps.</p>
                <p>These maps have been developed and designed by Byron Moldofsky and Mariange
                    Beaudry of the GIS and Cartography Office, Department of Geography and Planning,
                    University of Toronto.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
