<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:base="tei/" xml:id="donate">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Donate</title>
                <author>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>version 1, released <date when-iso="2024-01-01">1 January
                    2024</date></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority><orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>University of Toronto</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>170 St George Street, Suite 810</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Toronto, Ontario, Canada</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>M5R 2M8</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </authority>
                <availability>
                    <p>Copyright <orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>,
                            <date>2024</date></p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Distributed
                        under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0
                        International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) licence.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>Records of Early English Drama</title>
            </seriesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital. Information on original sources for transcriptions can be accessed
                    via the Document Descriptions.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Records of Early English Drama (REED) is an international scholarly project that
                    is establishing for the first time the context from which the drama of
                    Shakespeare and his contemporaries grew. Founded in 1976, REED has worked since
                    then to locate, transcribe, and edit historical documents containing evidence of
                    drama, secular music, and other communal entertainment and ceremony from the
                    Middle Ages until 1642, when the Puritans closed the London theatres.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change/>
            <!-- Add new major milestone changes to top, within <change> tags. For instance, addition of new collections. -->
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="donate_overview">
                <p> REED’s research, publications, and staff continue to be supported by grants and
                    gifts-in-kind from the Canadian, American, and British governments, various
                    foundations, the University of Toronto and Victoria University, and from
                    interested individuals from around the world. Personal donations, however, are
                    governed by the tax laws of the country of the donor. Donations sent directly to
                    the University of Toronto receive tax receipts applicable to Canadian tax laws.
                </p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="canadian_donors">
                <head>Canadian Donors</head>
                <p> Canadian donors have two options: </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Donating Online</hi></p>
                <p> If you are interested in making an online donation to REED, please visit the
                    Faculty of Arts and Science, English Department, giving page. </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Donating by Cheque</hi></p>
                <p> We can accept private gifts by cheque, made out to The University of Toronto
                    with ‘Records of Early English Drama’ in the memo line. Send your cheque to REED
                    and we will ensure it reaches the U of T Advancement Office. Our
                    address:<lb/><lb/> Records of Early English Drama, Jackman Humanities
                    Building<lb/> 170 St George St, Suite 810<lb/> University of Toronto<lb/>
                    Toronto, Ontario, Canada<lb/> M5R 2M8 </p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="american_british_donors">
                <head>American and British Donors</head>
                <p> American and British donors who wish to take advantage of the arrangements that
                    the University of Toronto has made with their national tax systems SHOULD NOT
                    donate online but follow these directions: </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">American Donors</hi></p>
                <p> United States donors may make a tax-deductible donation through the Associates
                    of the University of Toronto, a not-for-profit organization recognized under the
                    U.S. Internal Revenue Code, Section 501(c)(3), specifying that their gift is for
                    REED. For information about the Associates and how you may make such a gift,
                    please see the University’s How to Give page. Scroll down the list to
                    ‘International Gifts’ and click for further information. </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">British Donors</hi>
                </p>
                <p> Cheques should be made out to ‘CAF University of Toronto Fund T/70139430’ and
                    sent to:<lb/><lb/> Charities Aid Foundation<lb/> 25 Kings Hill Avenue<lb/> Kings
                    Hill<lb/> West Malling<lb/> Kent ME19 4TA<lb/><lb/> Please specify that your
                    donation is for Records of Early English Drama at the University of Toronto.
                    Transfers are made periodically by the Foundation to the U of T and we have been
                    assured that the amount donated for REED will be indicated. If you could let us
                    know that a donation has been made, we can acknowledge it in a timely fashion.
                </p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="other_donors">
                <head>Other Nationalities</head>
                <p> We regret that there are no arrangements in place to allow you to receive
                    specific tax relief. However, if you donate according to the procedures for
                    Canadian donors you will receive an official receipt from the University of
                    Toronto that you may be able to use in your country. </p>
                <p> Thank you very much for supporting REED. </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
