<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:base="tei/" xml:id="locations">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">How REED Defines Locations</title>
                <author>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>version 1, released <date when-iso="2024-03-06">06 March
                    2024</date></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority><orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>University of Toronto</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>170 St George Street, Suite 810</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Toronto, Ontario, Canada</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>M5R 2M8</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </authority>
                <availability>
                    <p>Copyright <orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>,
                            <date>2024</date></p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Distributed
                        under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0
                        International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) licence.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>Records of Early English Drama</title>
            </seriesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital. Information on original sources for transcriptions can be accessed
                    via the Document Descriptions.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Records of Early English Drama (REED) is an international scholarly project that
                    is establishing for the first time the context from which the drama of
                    Shakespeare and his contemporaries grew. Founded in 1976, REED has worked since
                    then to locate, transcribe, and edit historical documents containing evidence of
                    drama, secular music, and other communal entertainment and ceremony from the
                    Middle Ages until 1642, when the Puritans closed the London theatres.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change/>
            <!-- Add new major milestone changes to top, within <change> tags. For instance, addition of new collections. -->
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="Locations">
                <head>How REED Defines Locations</head>
<p>
    This list of locations and definitions was 
</p>
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="bold"
                                >Term&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</hi></cell>
                        <cell><hi rend="bold">REED
                            Definition</hi>&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</cell>
                        <cell><hi rend="bold"
                                >Example(s)&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</hi></cell>
                        <cell><hi rend="bold">Definition
                                source&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</hi></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row><cell><lb/></cell></row>
                    <row>

                        <cell><hi rend="italic">arena</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A level area in which sports, entertainments, and other public events
                            are held. Includes cockpits, tiltyards, animal baiting arenas.</cell>
                        <cell><ref target="https://ereeddev.library.utoronto.ca/entities/227798/">Bear Garden 3</ref>, <lb/>Tiltyard at Whitehall</cell>
                        <cell>New Oxford American Dictionary, 3rd ed. Amended.</cell>
                        <cell/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">bridge</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A structure forming or carrying a road, path, etc., which spans a body
                            of water, a roadway, a valley, or some other obstacle or gap, and allows
                            a person or vehicle to pass unimpeded over or across it.</cell>
                        <cell>London Bridge</cell>
                        <cell>OED 1. Amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">church</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A building for public Christian worship or rites such as baptism,
                            marriage, etc., traditionally cruciform in shape, and typically having a
                            tower, dome, or spire; distinguished originally from an oratory or place
                            of private prayer.</cell>
                        <cell>Westminster Abbey; Christ Church Newgate Street, church of; St Martin
                            Ludgate, church of</cell>
                        <cell>OED 1a.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">church <lb/>house</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A house owned by a church; esp. a building next to a church, in which
                            social events, meetings, etc., connected with the church are held; a
                            church hall. Also: a house provided by the church for a member of the
                            clergy; a parochial</cell>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell>OED</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">country</hi></cell>
                        <cell>The territory of a nation</cell>
                        <cell>England, France, Ireland, Scotland</cell>
                        <cell>OED 5. Amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">county</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An administrative division of England, Scotland, Wales, and
                            Ireland</cell>
                        <cell>Surrey, Sussex, Middlesex</cell>
                        <cell>OED I.</cell>
                        <cell/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">ecclesiastical area</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A geographic region formally connected to a religious organization,
                            such as a diocese, archdeaconry, etc. Does not include parishes.</cell>
                        <cell>Diocese of Winchester, Archdeaconry of Surrey</cell>
                        <cell/>

                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">gate</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An opening in a wall, made for the purpose of entrance and exit, and
                            capable of being closed by a movable barrier, the existence of which is
                            usually implied; said with reference to a city or other enclosure, or
                            the enclosure-wall of a large building, formerly also to the building
                            itself, where door or doors is now commonly employed.</cell>
                        <cell>Aldgate, Bishopsgate, Cripplegate</cell>
                        <cell>OED 1.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">guildhall</hi></cell>
                        <cell>The hall in which a guild met. From its use as a meeting-place for the
                            town and corporation often synonymous with ‘town-hall’</cell>
                        <cell>Bakers' Hall, Merchant Taylors' Hall</cell>
                        <cell>OED</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">hospital</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A house or hostel for the reception and entertainment of pilgrims,
                            travellers, and strangers; a hospice. Hence, one of the establishments
                            of the Knights Hospitallers. or an institution or establishment for the
                            care of the sick or wounded, or of those who require medical
                            treatment.</cell>
                        <cell>Bethlehem Hopsital</cell>
                        <cell>OED 1 and 3.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">Inn of Court</hi></cell>
                        <cell>The four sets of buildings in London (the Inner Temple, the Middle
                            Temple, Lincoln's Inn, and Gray's Inn) belonging to the four legal
                            societies which have the exclusive right of admitting persons to
                            practise at the bar, and hold a course of instruction and examination
                            for that purpose; hence, these four societies themselves.</cell>
                        <cell>Inner Temple, Middle Temple, Lincoln's Inn, Gray's Inn</cell>
                        <cell>OED 5c.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">liberty</hi></cell>
                        <cell>(a) An area of local administration distinct from neighbouring
                            territory and possessing a degree of independence. In extended use: a
                            precinct, a domain. Also in plural in same sense. (b) The district
                            outside a city over which its jurisdiction extends. Also in plural in
                            same sense. (c) Chiefly in plural and also with capital initial. An area
                            outside a prison within which, on payment of a security, certain
                            prisoners, esp. debtors, were permitted to reside.</cell>
                        <cell>Clink, St Bartholomew's Hospital, Tower of London</cell>
                        <cell>OED 6c.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">manor</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An estate of a lord, including both the land and the manor house or
                            mansion; a landed possession. Note: Manor houses themselves are
                            categorized as "residences" and may have different names from the manor
                            itself. If the name is the same, then the manor house name is
                            capitalized (eg, Holcombe Burnell Manor)</cell>
                        <cell>Paris Garden manor</cell>
                        <cell>OED 1. Emphasis and note added.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">open area</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An open space, often with poorly defined boundaries, such as a field,
                            park, forest, market, etc</cell>
                        <cell>Finsbury Fields, Lambeth Marsh, Lincoln's Inn Fields, Smithfield
                            Market, Covent Garden</cell>
                        <cell>OED "area" 1.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">other</hi></cell>
                        <cell>catch all for misfits; misc.</cell>
                        <cell>sewers</cell>
                        <cell/>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">parish</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An area or district having its own priest, vicar, or other incumbent
                            under the jurisdiction of a bishop (to whom tithes and ecclesiastical
                            dues were formally paid); a territorial subdivision of a diocese. The
                            smallest unit of local government in many rural areas.The existing
                            ecclesiastical parishes were adopted by the Tudor state for civil
                            purposes in a series of legislative measures beginning in the 1530s.
                            These involved the parish having local responsibility for vital
                            registration, highways, militia matters, and, above all, poor relief,
                            roles which were largely retained until the 1830s. </cell>
                        <cell>St Saviour Southwark, All Hollows Bread Street, St Margaret Fish
                            Street</cell>
                        <cell>OED 2a. and 3a. Amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">place of punishment</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A building or other location where people are disciplined for a crime
                            or other offence, where people are held while awaiting trial, or where
                            people are incarcerated.</cell>
                        <cell>Marshalsea Prison, Newgate prison, Tower Hill, Tyburn, Poultry
                            Compter</cell>
                        <cell>OED "prison" 1b. Significantly amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">playhouse</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An edifice specially adapted to dramatic representations</cell>
                        <cell>Rose Playhouse, Fortune Playhouse, Theatre playhouse</cell>
                        <cell>OED "theatre" 2a.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">property</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A piece of land under one ownership. Sometimes a landed estate.</cell>
                        <cell>Little Rose property, the Unicorn</cell>
                        <cell>OED 3c. Slightly amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">religious<lb/> house</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A house or building inhabited by a religious order; an abbey,
                            monastery, convent, etc.; places where the religious orders lived and
                            includes: priories, friaries, monasteries, nunneries, etc.</cell>
                        <cell>Charterhouse, Holywell Priory</cell>
                        <cell>OED. amended</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">private<lb/> residence</hi></cell>
                        <cell>The place where a person resides; the dwelling place or home of a
                            person (esp. one of some rank or distinction).</cell>
                        <cell>Hampton Court, Tower of London, St. James' Palace, Bishop of
                            Winchester's palace</cell>
                        <cell>OED 4a.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">school</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An establishment or institution for the formal education of children
                            or young people. Includes colleges and universities as well as grammar
                            schools, primary schools etc.</cell>
                        <cell>Westminster Grammar School, Eton, Trinity College Cambridge, St Paul's
                            School</cell>
                        <cell>OED II. 5a. Amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">settlement</hi></cell>
                        <cell> A collection of dwelling-houses and other buildings identified as a
                            single geo-political or administrative unit (such as a town or
                            city).</cell>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell>OED "village" 1a. and TEI def of settlement. Amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">street</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A path or way between different places, or leading to some place
                            (including lanes, alleys, roads)</cell>
                        <cell>Fleet Street, Rose Alley, Watling Street</cell>
                        <cell>OED "road" 4a.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">town hall</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A building used for the administration of local government, the
                            holding of court sessions, public meetings, entertainments, etc.; (in
                            early use also) a large hall used for such purposes within a larger
                            building or set of buildings.</cell>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell>OED 1a.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">victualling<lb/> house</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A house where victuals are supplied or sold; an eating-house, inn, or
                            tavern</cell>
                        <cell>Bell and Cock Inn, Boar's Head Inn</cell>
                        <cell>OED.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">ward</hi></cell>
                        <cell>An administrative division of a borough or city; originally, a
                            district under the jurisdiction of an alderman. Also, the people of such
                            a district collectively.In Anglo-Latin documents the wards (wardæ) of
                            London are mentioned by that name from the 12th cent., sometimes
                            designated by the name of the alderman and sometimes by their
                            locality.</cell>
                        <cell/>
                        <cell>OED 19a.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><hi rend="italic">water<lb/> feature</hi></cell>
                        <cell>A body or mass of standing or flowing water (natural or artificial),
                            irrespective of size or type; a sea, lake, river, etc.</cell>
                        <cell>River Thames, Great Conduit, Skinner's Well</cell>
                        <cell>OED "water" 11a. Amended.</cell>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <cell><lb/></cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
