<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:base="tei/" xml:id="series_methodology">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Series Methodology</title>
                <author>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>version 1, released <date when-iso="2017-03-03">3 March 2017</date></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority><orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>University of Toronto</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>170 St George Street, Suite 810</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Toronto, Ontario, Canada</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>M5R 2M8</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </authority>
                <availability>
                    <p>Copyright <orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>,
                        <date>2017</date></p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Distributed under a
                        Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-NC-SA
                        4.0) licence.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>Records of Early English Drama</title>
            </seriesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital. Information on original sources for transcriptions can be accessed via the
                    Document Descriptions.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Records of Early English Drama (REED) is an international scholarly project that is
                    establishing for the first time the context from which the drama of Shakespeare and his
                    contemporaries grew. Founded in 1976, REED has worked since then to locate, transcribe,
                    and edit historical documents containing evidence of drama, secular music, and other
                    communal entertainment and ceremony from the Middle Ages until 1642, when the Puritans
                    closed the London theatres.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change></change>
            <!-- Add new major milestone changes to top, within <change> tags. For instance, addition of new collections. -->
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

<text>
<body>
            <div xml:id="introduction">
                <head>Introduction</head>
                <p>From the start of the REED project, research areas have been defined geographically by
                    county and major city. Although the progress of several centuries has obscured or
                    drastically redesigned some county boundaries, REED observes county limits as recognized
                    by their contemporary, pre-1642 records. Thus, modern Cumbria reverts to its earlier
                    division into Cumberland and Westmorland.</p>
                <p>Important families sometimes had more than one residence in a county and occasionally it
                    has proved difficult to identify the exact location for family entertainments.
                    Households, therefore, are sorted under family name rather than parish or borough. Other
                    documents, such as statutes or visitation articles, relate to a diocese as a whole;
                    these are identified by diocese (as, for example, Diocese of Chester). Similarly, there
                    are county or quarter session records which cannot be pinpointed to a particular
                    location.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="selection">
                <head>Principles of Selection</head>
                <p>REED collections of records attempt to include all known references to dramatic, secular
                    musical, and mimetic ceremonial performances before 1642 by location. Performance has
                    been broadly defined to encompass nearly every mimetic, musical, or ritualistic form of
                    play used to entertain or otherwise engage an audience. Entries may record an actual and
                    identifiable performance or simply provide information that illuminates a performance
                    tradition. Musical performance includes all forms of secular music by itinerant or local
                    minstrels, fiddlers, musicians, and town waits in secular performance, as well as
                    information about musical instruments and practices, but it excludes singing and
                    instrumental music as part of public worship. Parish ales, wakes, revels, and fairs are
                    included only when it can be shown that they actually included entertainment such as
                    music, drama, baitings, or dancing. Liturgical ceremonial and drumming for militia
                    musters are not part of REED’s mandate.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="dating">
                <head>Dating</head>
                <p>The usefulness of the documents depends in large measure on the accuracy of their dating;
                    they have therefore been dated with care, by year and, whenever possible, to the month
                    and day. The writers of the documents nearly all assume that the year began on 25 March,
                    and for dates between 1 January and 24 March the years have routinely been advanced to
                    conform with modern practice. This is indicated by using a slash, as in '1 February
                    1476/7.'</p>
                <p>Records derived from accounts are dated in the heading according to the accounting year
                    (eg, 1611–12), with the accounting period or the rendering date, when only that is
                    known, given in the subheading (eg, <hi rend="italic">(18 October–17 October)</hi> or
                    <hi rend="italic">(rendered 26 February 1612/13)</hi>).</p>
                <p>If it can sometimes be difficult to date the account itself, it is often relatively easy
                    to date its entries at least roughly. Most entries are not dated within the accounts
                    themselves, but in nearly every account at least a handful of entries are either dated
                    or datable by day and month. These entries make it possible to determine whether an
                    account is in fairly good chronological order. Where possible, therefore, a date has
                    been provided for each relevant entry, giving, where there is not an exact date, the
                    limits of the date suggested by the chronology of the account. These dates can be
                    presumed with certainty to be the date on which the performer received payment and the
                    date of performance is therefore presumed likely to have been on or near that date.
                    Where the account is not chronological, or there are too few dated entries to tell, the
                    date given is that of the whole account.</p>
                <p>Ecclesiastical and civil court records present dating problems as well because the only
                    truly fixable date is the one on which the court was held. Therefore, the date that is
                    assigned to extracts from the courts is that of the court proceeding, while the probable
                    date of the performance, to the extent that it can be derived, is given in an endnote or
                    footnote to the text. When it is possible to trace the dates on which the case moved
                    through the several stages of its process, those dates are also given, whether in
                    subheadings for subsequent extracts concerning the case or in summaries of the process
                    in endnotes. The process in church courts seems to have remained fairly constant from
                    diocese to diocese; a full explanation of standard process can be found in David
                    Klausner (ed), <title>Herefordshire/Worcestershire</title>, REED (Toronto, 1990),
                    38–40.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="editorial">
                <head>Editorial Conventions</head>
                <p>Each record is preceded by a name or descriptive title, along with a brief identification
                    of its source. On a separate line the precise accounting period of the entry (where
                    known) and the manuscript account heading (where available) is given. Where folio or
                    page numbers have been supplied editorially, they are enclosed within square brackets.
                    The symbol (A) in the left margin indicates documents that are antiquarian.</p>
                <p>Bibliographic citations are included in full in editorial apparatus, with the exception
                    of standard reference works or books and articles that contain original transcriptions
                    of the documents. Such works are cited in short form by author, title, and page number
                    where they appear but a complete citation for each is included in the Bibliography
                    section.</p>
                <p>Place names and surnames are given in modern form in the editorial apparatus, where that
                    can be ascertained, and titles and family names of nobility and other public figures in
                    forms commonly used by historians. Succession numbers, where provided, follow the
                    absolute sequence given in <title>The Complete Peerage</title>. <title>The Complete
                        Peerage</title> and other standard reference works used for the purpose are listed
                    in the Bibliography, General section. Other surnames are usually cited in the most
                    common form for the individual occurring in the Records.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="transcription">
                <head>Transcription Conventions</head>
                <p>Within practical limits, the general layout of the originals has been preserved. Headings
                    and account totals are shown in the approximate position they occupy in the source.
                    Marginalia are indicated by the circled symbol 'm,' inserted in the text near their
                    occurrence in the MS; a circled 'r' or 'l' beside the marginale text indicates whether
                    it is in the right or left margin. Totals are transcribed only when all the amounts
                    making up the totals are also transcribed. In continuous prose, the paragraph divisions
                    of the manuscripts have been retained, but not the lineation. Where the layout of the
                    original is idiosyncratic (eg, a diagonal left margin), no attempt has been made to
                    reproduce that format.</p>
                <p>Dittography and other obvious scribal errors are noted. Decay, damage, or other problems
                    which adversely affect the legibility of the original are either briefly noted in a
                    footnote or discussed at length in an endnote following the record.</p>
                <p>Manuscript punctuation has been retained, except that excessive scribal pointing, most
                    manuscript braces, and all line fillers have been ignored. Virgules are indicated as /
                    and //.</p>
                <p>The spelling of the original has been preserved, along with the capitalization. 'ff' has
                    been retained for 'F'; the standard and elongated forms of 'I' are uniformly transcribed
                    as 'I.' Minuscules have been preferred where it has been difficult to distinguish
                    minuscules from majuscules. Ornamental capitals and display letters have been
                    transcribed as ordinary letters but are footnoted. Arabic '1' has been used for the 'i'
                    occasionally found in arabic numerals. Majuscule letters appearing in the middle of
                    words otherwise written in minuscules are presented as minuscules.</p>
                <p>Abbreviated words have been expanded, with italics to indicate letters supplied by the
                    editor. Where manuscripts yield insufficient evidence to judge individual scribal
                    habits, abbreviations are expanded to classical forms in Latin and modern British forms
                    in English. First names have been expanded wherever possible. However in cases where it
                    is impossible to determine what the scribe intended – whether, for example, 'minstr'
                    refers to one or several minstrels – the word has been left unexpanded.</p>
                <p>Abbreviations for sums of money ('li,' 's,' 'd,' 'ob' (for half-penny)), 'viz,' and 'etc'
                    or '&amp;c' and abbreviations cumbersome to expand, including those typical for weights
                    and measures ('lb' for 'pound'), are retained. 'Mr' and 'Dr' are left unexpanded when
                    introducing a proper name, but expanded when used as nouns or when occurring before
                    another title (eg, 'M<ex>aste</ex>r Mayor'). 'Xp-' and 'xp-' are expanded as
                    'Chr<ex>ist</ex>-' and ‘chr<ex>ist</ex>-’. A looped mark of abbreviation has been
                    expanded as '<ex>es</ex>' except when it follows an 'e': in this case it is expanded as
                    '<ex>s</ex>.' Where single minims are too many or too few by obvious scribal error,
                    an editorially corrected version is supplied in the text and the textual oddity is
                    noted. Otiose flourishes are ignored. Superlinear letters are lowered to the line except
                    when used with numerals ('x<hi rend="superscript">o</hi>,' 'xxiiij<hi rend="superscript"
                        >ti</hi>').</p>
                <p>Where two or more copies of the same document survive, the editor has chosen a base text
                    and collated significant variants. In all collations differences in capitalization, form
                    of abbreviation, word-division, and punctuation have been omitted.</p>
                <p>Editorial symbols and abbreviations used in the records text can be linked to from the
                    Helpful Links section in the right margin of individual Record pages, or from About the
                    Records in the upper navigation bar.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="translations">
                <head>About the Translations</head>
                <p>The documents have been translated as literally as possible. Unclear, technical, or
                    archaic terms, especially those pertaining to canon or common law, performance, and
                    music, are usually given a stock translation equivalent but receive a fuller treatment
                    in the glossaries.</p>
                <p>Capitalization and punctuation are in accordance with modern practice. As in the records
                    text, diamond brackets indicate obliterations and strike throughs, cancellations.
                    Cancellations are not always translated; they may be translated when the whole entry is
                    cancelled or when they seem to be of special interest or relevance. Round brackets
                    enclose words supplied editorially, most often because they are needed for grammatical
                    sense in English or to offer an alternative translation of a difficult or ambiguous
                    phrase.</p>
                <p>In translated documents also containing English, the English sections are normally
                    indicated with '<hi rend="italic">(English)</hi>,' but in some cases, in which the
                    syntax has become entangled, the English text appears in the translation in modern
                    spelling. All Latin vocabulary not found in the <title>Oxford Latin Dictionary</title>
                    or the <title>Dictionary of Medieval Latin from British Sources</title> is found in the
                    Latin Glossary. All Anglo-French vocabulary not found in the electronic edition of the
                    <title>Anglo-Norman Dictionary</title> (online at the <ref
                        target="http://www.anglo-norman.net/">Anglo-Norman Hub</ref>) is found in the
                    Anglo-French Glossary.</p>
            </div>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
