<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="records/REED.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:base="tei/" xml:id="visit">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">Visit REED</title>
                <author>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</author>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>version 1, released <date when-iso="2024-01-01">1 January
                    2024</date></edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority><orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>University of Toronto</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>170 St George Street, Suite 810</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Toronto, Ontario, Canada</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>M5R 2M8</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </authority>
                <availability>
                    <p>Copyright <orgName>Records of Early English Drama (REED)</orgName>,
                            <date>2024</date></p>
                    <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Distributed
                        under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0
                        International (CC BY-NC-SA 4.0) licence.</licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <seriesStmt>
                <title>Records of Early English Drama</title>
            </seriesStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital. Information on original sources for transcriptions can be accessed
                    via the Document Descriptions.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <projectDesc>
                <p>Records of Early English Drama (REED) is an international scholarly project that
                    is establishing for the first time the context from which the drama of
                    Shakespeare and his contemporaries grew. Founded in 1976, REED has worked since
                    then to locate, transcribe, and edit historical documents containing evidence of
                    drama, secular music, and other communal entertainment and ceremony from the
                    Middle Ages until 1642, when the Puritans closed the London theatres.</p>
            </projectDesc>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change/>
            <!-- Add new major milestone changes to top, within <change> tags. For instance, addition of new collections. -->
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="research_reed">
                <head>Doing Research at REED</head>
                <p> Resources of the REED office include important microfilm collections of original
                    documentation used by the REED project, as well as an extensive collection of
                    books and articles on early drama and music, palaeography, lexicography,
                    patronage, and topography. If you are interested in visiting REED to consult
                    these resources, please contact the REED Director of Research and General
                    Editor, <ref target="mailto:s.maclean@utoronto.ca">Sally-Beth MacLean</ref>. </p>
                <p> Some of our in-house editorial resources are also available online: the REED
                    Handbook for Editors (1980; revised 1990) and Palaeographic Checking Guidelines
                    (revised 2010). </p>
                <p> Further information about seeking access to unpublished transcripts held by REED
                    editors is found in the REED Executive Motion on Fair Use, passed on 27 May
                    2004: ‘All requests to consult unpublished materials (transcriptions and
                    manuscript facsimile reproductions) must be made directly to the REED collection
                    editor as copyright holder, who is free to share his or her work as he or she
                    wishes, rather than to the REED Editorial Office. Before permission to use or
                    cite unpublished materials can be granted, the collection editor and the
                    applicant must complete and sign a Memorandum of Fair Use form, which can be
                    downloaded from the REED website.’ The contact email addresses for appropriate
                    editors can be found on the Forthcoming Collections page. </p>
            </div>
            <div xml:id="reed_address">
                <head>Address</head>
                <p> Records of Early English Drama, Jackman Humanities Building<lb/> 170 St George
                    St, Suite 810<lb/> University of Toronto<lb/> Toronto, Ontario, Canada<lb/> M5R
                    2M8</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
